<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on Software Engineering Practices</title>
    <link>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on Software Engineering Practices</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 14:00:43 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a New Theme</title>
      <link>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Move static content to static Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png  should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png  Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title>
      <link>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/posts/goisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/posts/goisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Hugo uses the excellent Go html/template library for its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of similarities in Go templates.
This document is a brief primer on using Go templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/posts/hugoisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/posts/hugoisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Step 1. Install Hugo Go to Hugo releases and download the appropriate version for your OS and architecture.
Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.
More complete instructions are available at Install Hugo
Step 2. Build the Docs Hugo has its own example site which happens to also be the documentation site you are reading right now.
Follow the following steps:
 Clone the Hugo repository Go into the repo Run hugo in server mode and build the docs Open your browser to http://localhost:1313  Corresponding pseudo commands:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/chapter1/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/chapter1/1/</guid>
      <description>Object Oriented Programming Object Oriented Programming is a programming paragdigm based on the concept of real world objects which contains functions (real world procedures, also known as methods) and attributes (data containing characteristics about the object).
The philosphical approach of Object Oriented programming is to use the divide and conquer method towards software problems.
Described in Sun Tzu&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Art of War&amp;rdquo;
 It is the rule in war, if ten times the enemy&amp;rsquo;s strength, surround them; if five times, attack them; if double be able to divide them; if equal,engage them; if fewer, defend against them; if weaker, be able to avoid them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/chapter1/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/chapter1/2/</guid>
      <description>Debugging Debugging is a technique of finding and resolving of defects that prevent correct operations of software systems
In the early days of computing, debugging was cumbersome but now debugging is more seamless because of various tools called debuggers.
We can use debuggers in various languages and various IDEs.
Here are some of the debugging techniques for the most common IDEs in some common OOP languages.
Debugging Process: Steps involved in debugging are:  Identifying the problem Assigning the report to software engineer to the defect to verify that it is genuine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/chapter1/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/chapter1/3/</guid>
      <description>User Interface Design The philosophy of good user interface design is to make simple designs that promote self exploration. While the interface should be clean, the main functions should be easily visible and runnable within less interactions.
One of the approach to designs from Henry Pertovski is that faliure in design is imperative as design is an iterative process so more valuable feedback comes from faliures rather than successes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/chapter2/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/chapter2/1/</guid>
      <description>Project Organization and Management With companies facing increasing companies and change in technology, managing projects that last from a few weeks to several years can be a challenging task. Thankfully project organization allows this effort to be focused and efficiently targeted.
A project is defined as an undertaking that is:
 limited in time has a clear goal and a specific budget requiring a concerted effort  Hence tere are many facets of a project that must be managed by a project manager and the members of the teams undertaking that project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/chapter2/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/chapter2/2/</guid>
      <description>Communication Communication is very important in software engineering and various guidelines need to be followed to maintain effective communication within internal and external stakeholders.
Communication Skills in SE  Collaboration: Negotiating requirements Presentation: Presenting the system during a review Technical Writing: Writing proposals and project documentation Maanagement: Facilitate team meetings, find compromises, negotiate conflicts etc.  People need to communicate more in larger companies as there are more stakeholders and more project working on the same project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/chapter2/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/chapter2/3/</guid>
      <description>Software Lifecycle Models There are different questions in sofware development that lead to good software solutions. These questions are addressed by software development activites:
There are different questions in software development * Requirements Elicitation: What is the problem? * Requirements Analysis: Partition the problem into smaller pieces * System Design: Design solutions for * Object Design: What are the best mechanisms to implement the solution? * Implementation: How is the solution constructed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/chapter2/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/chapter2/4/</guid>
      <description>Scrum There are two types of process controls in software engineering. These are defined process controls and empirical process control.
Defined process control are models loke waterfall or the v-model where processes are planned, follow strict rules and avoid deviations. They do not deal with change very well.
Empirical process controls are not entirely planned and allow the teams to inspect and adapt. The spiral model is an example of this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/chapter2/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/chapter2/5/</guid>
      <description>Prototyping Software development deals with complex system. Since the developer is not the same person as the user, the design of the software system is complicated and thus they must communicate with the user.
The user is always right becuase after all the user is the one using the software. This is why prototpying is required to enable software engineers and developers to communicate with users or customers.
Types of Prototyping Prototyping generally focus on three main characteristics that are longetivity, fidelity and stage of a software system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/chapter2/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/chapter2/6/</guid>
      <description>UML Activity Diagram UML or Unified Modified Language is a visual language to visualize activites in software processes.
UML diagrams are of type softwarestructure diagrams or behaviour diagrams.
An activity diagram displays a sequence of actions, shows the behaviour of a system during analysis and models business processes.
These diagrams can model scrum or other software lifecycle models.
Here are some resources on exploring different types of diagrams and some more of UML activity diagrams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/examples/</guid>
      <description>Ubi loqui Mentem genus facietque salire tempus bracchia Lorem markdownum partu paterno Achillem. Habent amne generosi aderant ad pellem nec erat sustinet merces columque haec et, dixit minus nutrit accipiam subibis subdidit. Temeraria servatum agros qui sed fulva facta. Primum ultima, dedit, suo quisque linguae medentes fixo: tum petis.
Rapit vocant si hunc siste adspice Ora precari Patraeque Neptunia, dixit Danae Cithaeron armaque maxima in nati Coniugis templis fluidove. Effugit usus nec ingreditur agmen ac manus conlato.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>