<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docs on Software Engineering Practices</title>
    <link>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docs on Software Engineering Practices</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/examples/</guid>
      <description>Ubi loqui Mentem genus facietque salire tempus bracchia Lorem markdownum partu paterno Achillem. Habent amne generosi aderant ad pellem nec erat sustinet merces columque haec et, dixit minus nutrit accipiam subibis subdidit. Temeraria servatum agros qui sed fulva facta. Primum ultima, dedit, suo quisque linguae medentes fixo: tum petis.
Rapit vocant si hunc siste adspice Ora precari Patraeque Neptunia, dixit Danae Cithaeron armaque maxima in nati Coniugis templis fluidove. Effugit usus nec ingreditur agmen ac manus conlato.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/project_organization/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swopnilnep.github.io/software-engineering-practices/docs/project_organization/1/</guid>
      <description>Project Organization and Management With companies facing increasing companies and change in technology, managing projects that last from a few weeks to several years can be a challenging task. Thankfully project organization allows this effort to be focused and efficiently targeted.
A project is defined as an undertaking that is:
 limited in time has a clear goal and a specific budget requiring a concerted effort  Hence tere are many facets of a project that must be managed by a project manager and the members of the teams undertaking that project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>